你需要有个人帮你把沙袋稳住
You need someone to steady your bag.
你愿意帮忙吗
Are you offering?
当然
Yeah. Sure.
好的
All right.
漂亮
Nice.
-谢谢你  -乐意效劳
- Thank you. - Anytime.
好了  接下来是转牌圈[德州扑克术语]
All right. Here comes The Turn.
亲爱的  实际上这叫河牌圈
Mm. Actually, sweetie, it's called The River.
没错
Right. Right.
第五张公共牌叫"河牌圈"
The, uh, fifth community card is called "The river"
或者叫"第五圈"
or "Fifth street."
你已经入门了  孩子
Now you're on the trolley, kid.
那...谁赢了
So... who won?
实际上  你一直占优
Oh. Well, actually, you had me
直到最后这张
until the river.
你摸到了第三张杰克
Mm-hmm. And you got a third jack,
三张杰克比三张九要大
and trip Jacks beat trip 9s.
-你赢了  -别泄气  宝贝儿
- You win. - Well, don't sweat it, sweetheart.
这只是你的第一堂课而已
Just your first lesson.
要不咱们今晚就玩到这里吧
What do you say we call it a night?
什么  别  咱们继续
What? No. Let's keep playing.
-洗牌然后发牌  -亲爱的  你们好啊
- Shuffle up and deal. - Ah, hello, darlings.
这是干嘛呢
Oh, what's all this?
老爸在教我无限额德州扑克的基本规则
Dad's teaching me the basics of no-limit texas hold'em.
我太震惊了  竟然在赌博
I'm shocked--shocked-- there's gambling in here.
算我一个
Deal me in.
晚上好  贝克特探长
Good evening, Detective Beckett.
死者名叫保罗·芬奇
Victim's name is Paul Finch.
资料显示  这是他的车
According to the registration, it's his car.
还有什么关于他的资料吗
What do we know about him?
我们查了一下他的亲属  找到了他妻子
We ran him for next of kin, found his wife.
她正在赶来  还查到了他的犯罪记录
She's on her way in. And his rap sheet.
他是个小偷
He's a thief...
劫过几间银行  还有几次联手入室抢劫
Couple of bank jobs, some corporate B&Es.
但他已经好多年没有被逮着了
But he hasn't been arrested in a few years.
所以说  要么是他运气极佳
So he's either really lucky...
要么就是他金盆洗手了
Or he's out of the game.
死因是什么
What happened?
他是被电刑致死的
I'd say he was electrocuted.
从烧灼程度来看
That had to be pretty high voltage
电压一定很高
for him to get burns like that.
当然了
Well, sure.
你只要把这些线路直接和点火系统相连
You connect these leads directly into the ignition system,
然后再让引擎高速转动就行
you rev the engine high enough...
看上去凶手是想拷问他
Looks like they were trying to torture him,
但结果却把他弄死了
but ended up killing him instead.
不管怎样  都很痛苦
Either way, it wasn't pleasant.
不管凶手是谁
You know, whoever did this
他不是想借此传递信息
either wanted to send a message
就是想从他这里得到什么
or needed something from him.
一个退休的小偷身上能有什么...
What would somebody need from a retired...
怎么了
What?
他的眼睛是闭着的
His eyes are closed.
你们来之前有人碰过尸体吗
Did anyone touch the body before you came here?
没  我来的时候就这样了
Nope. It was like that when I got here.
一定是凶手在他死后帮他合上的
The killer must have closed 'em postmortem.
这意味着凶手认识死者
That means he knew the victim.
我觉得他可能是对自己的行为心存愧疚
I would say, he probably felt guilty about what he had done,
想要抹去这种罪恶感
wanted to erase it.
让鉴证组检查一下车里
Have C.S.U. sweep the cars,
我们用烟熏处理一下尸体
and let's fume the body.
说不定能在他的眼皮上发现指纹
Maybe we'll get some prints off of his eyelids.
好的
You got it.
这是什么
What is it?
你看呢
You tell me.
也许杀他的凶手
Maybe he was murdered by
是 "王子"普林斯[美国歌手  使用类似标记作为自己的代号]
the artist formerly known as Prince.
芬奇太太  我们很同情您的遭遇
Mrs. Finch, we're very sorry for your loss.
这个东西
Does this...
你看着眼熟吗
look familiar to you at all?
不  很抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
我知道我丈夫曾是个什么样的人
Look, I know what my husband was,
但是保罗自从出狱以后就洗手不干了
but Paul had been out of the game since he left prison.
我们结婚时  他就发誓不再行窃
When we got married, he swore off taking scores.
直到几星期前
Then a few weeks ago,
他说他要帮朋友做点事
he said he had to go do something for a friend.
他有说是什么人或者做什么事吗
Did he tell you what or who?
没有
No.
我求他不要去做  但是他
I begged him not to do it, but he...
他说他很久以前亏欠过这个人
He said he owed the guy from way back.
探长  保罗是个小偷
Paul was a thief, Detective,
但他盗亦有道
but he had this sense of honor.
这一点上他是很传统的
He was old-fashioned like that.
他是个好人  探长
He was a good man, Detective.
我是说  谁都知道他曾犯过错
I mean, god knows he had his faults,
但是...这个
But... this?
他不该落得如此下场
He didn't deserve this.
这家伙为了做这件事重出江湖
So the guy comes out of retirement
结果却因此丧命
for one job and ends up dead.
这绝对不是巧合
That cannot be a coincidence.
没错  什么事能让一个退休多年的人
Yeah, what lures a guy who's been retired for years
重操旧业呢
back into the game?
肯定是件大事
Must've been something big.
刚才劫案组打电话过来
That was robbery on the phone.
他们上报了前天发生的一起入室抢劫案
They logged in a break-in at a branch of
地点是曼哈顿互惠银行的一家分行
Manhattan Mutual the day before yesterday.
抢银行  这符合芬奇的犯罪记录
Bank heist. That fits with finch's profile.
-还有什么细节吗  -没有
- Did they have any details? - Nope.
他们正在派一个新人过来
They're sending the new guy up now.
那人就是我
And that would be me.
最近还好吧  兄弟
Oh-ho! What's up, bro?
你调动了怎么都不和我说一声
Why didn't you tell me you transferred?
你知道的  我一向随遇而安嘛
Ah, you know, I been settling in.
各位  这是我好兄弟汤姆·戴明
Hey, uh, this is my boy-- Tom Demming.
他是54分局最优秀的警察之一
He was one of the best cops back at the 54th.
-这是我的搭档莱恩  -你好
- This is my partner--Ryan. - How you doing?
-很高兴认识你  -我也是
- Hey, nice to meet you, man. - You, too.
-这是理查德·卡塞尔  -那个作家  对吧
- Richard Castle. - Yeah, the author, right?
没错
That's right.
这位是贝克特探长
And this is Detective Beckett.
-我们见过了  -是的  你好
- Yeah, we met. - Yes. Hi.
你好
Hi.
言归正传  保罗·芬奇
So Paul Finch, huh?
他是这里为数不多的
He's one of the few guys on the island
用这种方法行窃的小偷之一
who could've taken a score like that.
哪种方法
Like what?
几个职业小偷打通了金库
A couple of pros tunnel into the vault,
钻开了一个保险箱
drill open a safe deposit box,
除了百露牌古龙水味道外  没留任何痕迹
leave nothing behind but the great smell of Brut.
你觉得芬奇不可能
And you think that finch couldn't
单靠一人之力做到这些吗
have pulled this off on his own?
不可能  这起码得两个人才能做到
Nah, it's a 2-man job at the minimum.
肯定还有另一个人在场
There's definitely another player
负责帮他望风
floating around out there.
我们已经着手调查
Well, we've run a search
他的通话记录和财务状况
for his phone records and financials,
但愿我们能找到
so hopefully we'll find something
把他和别人联系上的线索
that ties him to a partner.
说不定是芬奇的同伙在得手后背弃了他
Or maybe the partner turned on Finch after the robbery,
觉得他再也没有利用价值了
decided he didn't need him anymore.
不管怎样  可以肯定
Either way, we know that
抢劫案和杀人案是有联系的
the robbery and the homicide are connected.
为了偷一个保险箱如此大动干戈
That seems like an awful lot of trouble
未免也太麻烦了点吧
for one safe deposit box.
没错  而且里面还有几堆现金原封未动
Yeah. And they left stacks of cash untouched.
楼下的同事听说我接手这案子时
The guys downstairs thought I was nuts
都觉得我是个疯子
when I hopped on this case,
但我就是喜欢怪异的案子
but I like the weird ones.
那正好  贝克特也喜欢怪异的案子
Hmm. How about that? Beckett likes the weird ones, too.
没错
Yeah.
那箱子里究竟有什么东西
What could be in that box
值得让人又是打地道又是杀人呢
that would be worth digging a tunnel to and killing for?
钻石  德国无记名债券
Diamonds? German bearer bonds?
纳粹宝藏
Nazi gold?
这个我们目前还不知道
Ah, we still don't know yet.
银行联系失主时遇上点困难
The bank had some trouble locating the owner,
但他应该下午就会过来了
but he's supposed to be coming in this afternoon.
你愿不愿意和我一起进行审讯
Would you like to join me for the interrogation?
好啊  当然愿意
Yeah. Yeah, I'd love to.
好的
Good.
另外  我需要你们去道上查一下
Meanwhile, I'm gonna need you guys to hit the street
把和芬奇有联系的人统计一下
and see if you can scare up any of Finch's associates--
也许其中就有曾和他合伙盗窃的人
Maybe anyone that he's taken scores with in the past
或者是他曾亏欠过的人  多谢
or people that he owes. Thank you.
没问题
You got it.
那我干什么
What can I do?
你可以在一边看着
You could watch.
两个礼拜前  我还两次救过你的命呢
Two weeks ago, I saved your life twice.
感谢你能来  卡纳先生
Thank you for coming in, Mr. Cana.
叫我弗雷德就好
Call me Fred.
我们一定会竭尽所能
And obviously, we're gonna do everything we can
帮你找回被盗的财产
to help you recover your stolen property.
保险箱里究竟装了什么
Uh, what exactly was in the box?
-邮票  -邮票?
- Stamps. - Stamps?
是的  我收集的
Yeah, I collect 'em.
你过了这么久才来找我们
It kinda surprises me
这一点让我很惊讶
it took you so long to reach out to us.
银行工作人员说
The folks at the bank said
过去几天里
they left you a half a dozen
他们留了好几条言给你
messages over the last couple of days.
我很忙的  知道吗
Well, I been busy, you know?
我的工作量很大
I been working a lot.
那你是从事什么工作的
And what is it that you do?
我从事私人保安的
I'm in, uh, private security.
你收藏的那些邮票能值多少钱
This stamp collection, how much was it worth exactly?
这种东西很难去明码标价的
Well, it's hard to put a price tag on an item like that
因为这里面倾注了很多情感投资
Because of, you know, the sentimental value.
那还有谁知道你把邮票收在银行里
And who else knew that you were keeping it at the bank?
只有部分其他的邮票收藏家
Just a select group of other stamp enthusiasts
这些人都和我是老交情
with whom I formed... relationships over the years.
那你成为集邮者多久了  弗雷德
So how long you been a philatelist, Fred?
你说话注意点  我可不是干那行的
Hey, watch your mouth, pal. Fred Cana don't go that route.
集邮就是收集邮票的意思  卡纳先生
Philately is the study of stamps, Mr. Cana,
如果你真是个收藏家  理应知道这个词的意思
which you would know if you were, in fact, a collector.
老实说吧  箱子里装的到底是什么
Come on, Fred. What's really in the box, huh?
他们从你那里偷走了什么
What'd they steal from you?
我才懒得理你这套废话
I don't have to take this crap.
我可是受害者
I'm the victim here.
你们俩盘查过那些非常嫌疑犯[美国电影]了吗
Hey, you guys rounding up the Usual Suspects?
是的  但是所有哈雷姆区的小混混都说
Yeah, and every hood this side of Harlem
芬奇已经洗手不干很多年了
says Finch has been out of action for years.
贝克特人呢
Where's Beckett?
她和美国上尉[漫画人物]和弗雷德·卡纳在一起
Oh, she and Captain America are in there with Fred Cana.
弗雷德·卡纳
Fred Cana?
是啊  他就是那个租了保险...
Yeah, he's the guy who rented the safety...
埃斯波西托警员
Officer Esposito!
现在是埃斯波西托警探了  弗雷德
Actually, it's Detective Esposito now, Fred.
恭喜你了
Congratulations.
弗雷德是维克托·雷辛的跟班
Fred here is a bagman for Victor Racine.
维克托·雷辛是谁
Who's Victor Racine?
是个黑帮头目
He's a syndicate man.
他在犯罪组织者和合法商人之间
made the leap from organized crime
不停地变换身份以掩人耳目
to legitimate businessman while no one was looking.
雷辛人脉发达  没人动得了他
Racine is connected and untouchable.
你应当深有体会吧
You oughta know.
埃斯波西托和他的搭档
Esposito and his old partner
几年前曾经试图对他下手
tried to touch him a few years back.
要不要我对你动手试试
How about I touch you instead?!
来试试啊  硬汉子
Come on! Come on, tough guy!
别这样  你先出去
Come on. Take a walk.
好了吧  他这种人不值得你动手
All right? He's not worth it. Man...
刚才那是搞的什么鬼
What the hell was that all about?
他是维克托·雷辛的手下
He works for victor Racine.
那又怎样
So?
维克托·雷辛杀了我的搭档
Victor Racine killed my partner.
他叫艾克  艾克·松顿
His name was Ike. Ike Thornton.
我在54分局的时候和他是搭档
We partnered up back when I was at the 54th.
我们当时在有组织犯罪调查组工作
We worked the organized crime task force.
维克托·雷辛是我们的目标人物
Victor Racine was our target...
直到某天  艾克没有来上班
Until one day, Ike didn't come into work.
他就好像失踪了一样
It's like he just disappeared.
更糟糕的是
To make matters worse,
内务处的人来找我们
Internal Affairs came around here
问了一堆问题  好像艾克已经被收买了一样
asking all these questions, talking like ike had gone over,
好像他在帮雷辛做事一样
that he was working for Racine.
这种事根本就是胡扯
It was an absolute load of crap.
几天过后
Couple of days later,
几个小孩在码头旁找到了艾克的车
some kids found Ike's car out by the docks...
弹痕累累  座位上全是血迹
shot to hell, blood all over the seats.
完全是职业杀手的行事作风
All the hallmarks of a professional hit.
没错  只是这事我们无法联系到雷辛身上
Yeah, only we couldn't tie it back to Racine.
他的手下把艾克的尸体丢了
His guys had dumped Ike's body
以致我们没法找到他
so that we could never find it.
这事过后  部门把整个行动都取消了
The department shut down the whole operation after that.
我就被调到了这里  但我可以肯定的是
I transferred here. But I know one thing--
如果弗雷德·卡纳有个保险箱
If Fred Cana has a safe deposit box,
肯定是为了雷辛保管东西的
it's because he's holding something for Racine.
里面装的肯定不是邮票
And it ain't no stamps.
他要血债血还
He wants blood.
这不奇怪  现在看来
Well, I don't blame him. From the look of it,
我想雷辛是因为芬奇偷他的东西杀了他
I'm guessing Racine had Finch killed for stealing from him.
这也解释了他为何要严刑拷打他
Well, that explains why he was tortured--
为了让他供出同党
So he'd give up his partner.
无论他们从保险箱里偷走了什么
You know, whatever they stole from that safe deposit box,
雷辛都非常想拿回来
Racine wants it back bad.
但是他是怎么发现是芬奇干的呢
Yeah, but how did he get onto Finch in the first place?
也许他认出了古露牌古龙水的味道
Maybe he recognized the great smell of Brut.
我确定雷辛是那种有耳目的人物
I'm sure that Racine is the kind of guy who has his sources.
那么你想让我们的集邮家
So you like our stamp collector
代替雷辛接受制裁
for doing the deed on Racine's behalf?
是啊  不过我们询问过
Sure, except we called.
他有目击证人能够证实他的不在场证明
He has witnesses willing to corroborate his whereabouts.
-他当然有  -我们没有其他证据了
- Of course he does. - And we have no proof otherwise.
说到证据  鉴证组刚送来犯罪现场
Oh, speaking of which, they brought up the CSU report
的报告  车子被擦拭过
on the crime scene. The car was wiped down.
除了芬奇和他妻子的指纹  找不到其他人的指纹
Other than Finch and his wife, we got no usable prints.
而且我们还不知道那个金属标志
And we still don't have an ID on that metal symbol
-代表什么 -同时"集邮家"有不在场证明
- we found. - Meanwhile, our stamp collector has an alibi,
我们现在没有证据
and we currently have no evidence.
下一步应该怎么办
So what is our next step?
我们和劫案的真正受害人谈谈
We talk to the real victim of our robbery--
维克托·雷辛先生
Mr. Victor Racine.
很大胆  我喜欢你的办案风格
Bold. I like your style.
什么  你认为他是那种
What, you think he's the kind of guy
随便就告诉你保险箱里是什么
who's just gonna tell us what's in that box
或是承认谋杀的人
or maybe admit to killing the thief?
学着点  卡塞尔  学着点
Watch and learn, Castle. Watch and learn.
什么风把你们给吹过来了
To what do I owe this pleasure, huh?
曼哈顿互惠银行的一个保险箱
A safe deposit box at Manhattan Mutual
昨晚被盗了  雷辛先生
was broken into the other night, Mr. Racine.
保险箱的主人是你的一位合作者  弗雷德·卡纳
It was registered to an associate of yours-- Fred Cana.
真别说  现在世道真是不好
You don't say? What's this world coming to, huh?
卡纳先生声称保险箱里保存着
Mr. Cana claims that the box contained
他的邮票收藏
his stamp collection?
我从不知道卡纳先生会对我
Well, I've never known Mr. Cana to lie...
说谎
to me.
我们相信保险箱里的东西
Well, we believe that it held something
可能要比邮票有价值  也许是你的东西
a little bit more valuable-- maybe something of yours.
真的吗  为什么这么说
Oh, really? And why is that?
因为涉嫌抢劫的一名嫌疑人
Because one of the guys involved in the robbery
昨晚被发现死于停车场
was found murdered in a parking garage last night.
事实上  芬奇先生在死前被拷打过
Well, actually, Mr. Finch was tortured before he was killed.
如果仅仅是偷了邮票
Now why would someone do that
为什么会有人拷打他
if all he stole were stamps?
你昨晚在哪里
Where were you last night?
在家
Home.
我有全天随身保镖证明
And I have around-the-clock bodyguards...
我昨天的行踪
who can attest to my whereabouts,
不过你们并不觉得是我杀的芬奇
but you don't think I killed Finch.
你们认为我让手下干的
You assume I had somebody do it for me,
你们来这是为了
so you're here just to...
炫技  是不是
count coup, aren't you?
抱歉  什么意思
Sorry. What was that?
是指平原印第安人把打斗中
The Plains Indians considered it an act of bravery
能够在不受伤的情况下接近对手并触摸对手
to get close enough to one of their enemies
-的行为视为勇敢  我的头发  -还不错
- to touch him with a coup stick. Is my hair... - looks good.
谢了
Thanks.
保险箱里的东西
This item or items that were in the safety deposit box,
假设说很有价值
if they're so valuable,
你们为何不去全力捉拿芬奇先生
why aren't you out chasing down Mr. Finch's associate
的那位搭档呢
in this endeavor?
毕竟  有句古话说的好
After all, you know what the old saying is--
盗亦"无"道
no honor among thieves.
瞧  我说什么来着  浪费时间
See, what'd I say? Waste of time.
干的漂亮  探长
Well played, Detective.
过奖了  探长
Thank you, Detective.
干的漂亮?  他全都否认了
"Well played"? All he did was deny it.
-从否认里可以得到很多信息  -比如说
- Well, you can learn a lot from a denial. - Like what?
比如说雷辛还没有找到芬奇的同伙
Like Racine hasn't found Finch's partner yet.
因为如果雷辛知道了同伙是谁或其下落
Because Racine would never point us in that direction
他是不会给我们指出这条线索的
if he already knew who or where the partner was.
他一定很想找到那个人
He must want this guy pretty bad
不惜让警察替他跑腿
if he's willing to have the cops do his legwork for him.
我们先找到芬奇的同伙对雷辛有什么好处
How does it help Racine if we find Finch's partner first?
雷辛人脉广泛  他不费吹灰之力
Racine's connected. He'd have no trouble
就可以找人在监狱干掉芬奇的同伙
having Finch's partner killed in jail.
好  我们马上到
Okay. We'll be right there.
蕾妮准备好烟熏尸体了
Lanie's ready to fume the body.
好吧  你们回停尸房
All right, you guys head back to the morgue.
我去看看芬奇财产状况的调查有什么结果
I'm gonna go see if Finch's financials have come in yet.
好的
Okay.
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
这太酷了
That is so cool.
-我拍照你介意吗  -随便你
- Do you mind if I take pictures? - Knock yourself out.
不过要是照片传到网上
But if any of them end up on the internet,
我会抓到你并痛扁一顿
I will hunt you down and hurt you.
那么
So...
和那位帅哥劫案探长怎么回事
What's with the handsome robbery detective?
戴明吗
Demming?
我们只是一起办案  就这样
Oh, we're just working the case together. That's all.
是啊  不过话说回来
Mm-hmm. But then again,
你和卡塞尔共事一年了
you have been working with castle for a year
什么都没发生
and not a damn thing has happened, so...
我们打赌来着
we had a pool going.
因为你们俩我赔了不少钱
I lost a lot of money on you two.
伙计们
You guys.
凶手替被害人合眼时
Yahtzee. The killer left a print
留下了指纹  查一查
when he closed our victim's eye. Let's run it.
怎么了
What?
指纹找到了匹配者
We got a match on the print,
不过匹配者已经死亡
but the guy it belongs to is dead.
-不可能  -除非他是僵尸
- But that's impossible. - Unless he's a zombie.
不是僵尸
Not a zombie.
是个警察
A cop.
艾塞克
Isaac...
"艾克" 松顿
"Ike" Thornton.
-埃斯波西托以前的搭档  -他还活着
- Esposito's old partner? - He's alive?
我出席了他的葬礼
I went to his funeral,
和他的妻子握了手
held his wife's hand.
现在你告诉我他还活着
And now you're telling me he's alive
替雷辛卖命  谋杀了芬奇
and working for Racine, that he murdered Finch?
这是一出完美的人间蒸发
It was the perfect disappearing act.
他知道所有人都会认为
He knew that everyone would think
是雷辛派人杀了他
that Racine had killed him
并弃尸他处
and dumped his body somewhere.
他不会那样做的  那样对不起警徽也对不起我
Nah, I don't see how he could do it, to the badge, to me?
-我可以为他挡子弹  -埃斯波西托
- I would've taken a bullet for him. - Esposito.
这位是内务处的霍利威尔督察
This is Lieutenant Holliwell from internal affairs.
我们见过
We've met.
-你通知内务处了  -没有
- You called I.A.? - No.
我为了保护你给他们打了电话
I called 'em for your protection.
抱歉  警探
I'm sorry, Detective.
我并不喜欢被证明是对的
I don't really enjoy being proved right.
是啊  当然不会
No, of course not.
我想你是调查艾克·松顿失踪
I take it you were the investigating officer
-的那位警官  -没错
- when Ike Thornton disappeared? - I was.
你是怎么怀疑到他的
And what put you onto him in the first place?
雷辛总是抢先我们一步
Racine was always one step ahead of us,
就好像他总是未卜先知
like he always knew what we were thinking.
没用多长时间我们就发现
It didn't take too much to figure out
有警察向他通风报信
that he was being tipped off by a cop.
幸好当时有位线人能够作证
Luckily, we had an informant at the time that confirmed it,
但是在我们缉捕松顿之前
but before we were able to arrest Thornton,
他失踪了
he disappeared.
很可能是发现我们要逮捕他
Most likely found out that we were coming for him.
找到他车的时候  我们就认为雷辛把他杀了
When we found his car, we just assumed Racine killed him.
看来是他把松顿拉入伙了
Looks like he brought him into the family instead.
松顿和你联系过吗
Has Thornton contacted you?
什么意思  和我联系
What do you mean, contacted me?
你在指控我拍档什么罪名
What exactly are you accusing my partner of?
-我没有指控  我是询问  -问什么
- I'm not accusing. I'm asking. - Asking what...
我是否知道一切  是否参与其中
If I knew all along, if I was part of it?
- 我没有  -这是个精心策划的骗局
- The answer's no. - It was such an elaborate hoax.
看起来需要
It seems like it would take
不少谋划和帮助
a little bit of planning, a little help.
我已经告诉你了  我不知道
I just told you, I didn't know.
你想让我干嘛  要我测谎吗
What do you want me to do, take a poly?
那你会接受测谎吗
Would you take a polygraph test?
-等等  -如果这会让你不再纠缠我
- Wait a minute-- - If it'll get you off my back.
-埃斯波西托 你不需要  -我想做
- Esposito, you don't have to do this. - I want to.
很好  我办公室  一小时后
Good. My office. One hour.
那家伙太过分了
That guy was out of line back there.
如果在他的立场  我也会问同样的问题
I'd be asking the same questions if I was in his shoes.
你可以和我谈谈
You know you can talk to me, right?
我把那一切都忘了  兄弟
I put all that stuff behind me, bro.
我留下唯一的纪念
The only thing I have left from back then...
就是这个
is this right here.
那时候  我还在54分局
Back in the day, when I was in the 54th,
每个人都戴着一个
everybody used to carry one of these with 'em.
是自豪的象征  知道吗
It was like a sense of pride, you know?
艾克也有一个
Ike had one of those?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. Why?
让我看看
Let me see it.
54分局
The 54th.
肯定是他和芬奇搏斗的时候弄断的
It must have broken off when he was struggling with Finch.
真是他
It was him.
如果你退出这案子
You know no one would blame you
没人会怪你
if you stepped off this case.
不
No.
不管是不是搭档
Partner or not...
他都杀了人
he killed a man.
这家伙这些年活得像幽灵般
This guy's pulled a ghost routine for years--
放弃了他原来的生活  他的朋友
gave up his old life, his friends.
如果没人帮忙  他不可能
A guy can't pull a disappearing act like that
-凭空消失  -他有雷辛的帮助
- without help from somebody. - He had Racine's help.
有没有雷辛他都结婚了  是吧  有孩子
Well, Racine or no Racine, he was married, right, has a kid?
他们一定知道
They must have known.
上个月见过卡萝  她毫不知情
I saw Carol last month. She doesn't know anything.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
见鬼  我什么都不确定了
Hell, I'm not sure about anything anymore.
你去哪
Where you going?
接受测谎  证明我的清白
Take a poly, clear my name.
把他妻子找来  看看她知道些什么
Go pick up the wife. Let's see what she knows.
很抱歉  我不相信你
I'm sorry. I don't believe you.
他拇指指纹在被害人身上  卡萝
His thumbprint's on our victim's body, Carol.
他活着  别无他解
He's alive. There's no other explanation.
他们没找到艾克的尸体  我不知道
Well, they never recovered Ike's body, so I don't know.
可能有人把他的拇指砍了下来
Someone could've cut off his thumb and--
是啊  可能是那样  不过你知道不是
Yes, they could've done that, but you know they didn't.
拜托  卡萝  这么多年
Come on, Carol. It's been years.
像你这么漂亮的女人怎么会找不到伴侣
An attractive woman like you hasn't found someone new?
对单亲妈妈来说并非易事
It's not easy when you're a single mom.
这些都和你们无关
Not that that's any of your business.
你们知道警察
You know what you get
在被通缉的时候去世会得到什么吗
when a cop dies with a warrant out on him?
告诉你们不会得到什么吧
Well, I'll tell you what you don't get.
得不到灵柩覆盖国旗的荣誉
You don't get a folded flag and you sure as hell
-你肯定也没有抚恤金  -不过
- don't get a penny of his pension. - And yet, you
你还是有办法支付抵押贷款
somehow manage to make mortgage payments--
如果艾克活着  就意味着我们还是夫妻
If Ike is alive, that means we're still married.
你们不能强迫我作对我丈夫不利的证词
And you can't compel me to testify against my spouse.
她知道他还活着  但是她知不知道
She knew he was alive, but did she know
他在为雷辛卖命呢
he was working for Racine?
她是个警察的妻子  她知道自己的权利
She's a cop wife and she knows her rights.
从她嘴里别想套出什么
Good luck getting anything out of her.
她也许会跟我谈
She might talk to me.
看看谁通过了测谎
Oh. Look who passed his poly.
感觉那个霍利威尔有点失望
Had the feeling that Holliwell was kinda disappointed.
她认识我
She knows me.
我可能会让她开口
I might be able to get her to open up.
好吧  早上去她家一趟
All right, take a run at her in the morning.
我派一个小队去她的住所监视
And I'll get a unit down to the house
-以防艾克现身  -好吧
- in case Ike decides to show up. - Right.
背叛  谎言  欺骗
Betrayal, lies, deceit--
听起来像是我第一段婚姻
sounds like my first marriage.
-怎么了  -我在想
- What? - I'm trying to figure out
那个保险箱里到底是什么这么重要
what was so damn important in that safe deposit box
值得芬奇和他的同伙去冒生命危险
that Finch and his partner would risk their lives that way.
你给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
-戴明  -我正打给你呢
- Demming. - I was just calling you.
真是巧  我正要来找你
What a coincidence. I was just coming to see you.
天啊  "巧"得像我们在办同一件案子
Wow. It's like we're all on the same case.
埃斯波西托告诉我艾克的情况
Esposito told me about Ike.
你有什么线索吗
You have a lead on him yet?
没有  还在查
No. We're working on it.
芬奇的同伙呢
What about Finch's partner?
电话和财产方面
Ah, there's nothing in his phone
都没有指向具体某个人
or his financials that points to one.
但是银行安保录像终于送来了
But the bank surveillance tapes finally came in.
明早我会仔细检查一遍的
I was gonna scrub 'em in the morning.
如果芬奇是在最近几周踩的点
If Finch cased the joint in the last couple of weeks--
那位神秘同伙可能跟他在一起
Then maybe the mystery partner went with him.
完全正确  你想帮忙吗
Exactly. You want to join me?
是啊  我很乐意
Yeah. Yeah, I'd love to. Great.
太好了  明早见
I'll see you in the morning.
好  明天见  晚安
Okay, great. I'll see you. Good night.
晚安
Good night.
卡塞尔  我能请教些问题吗
Castle, can I ask you something?
你和贝克特在交往吗
You and beckett-- is there, uh, something going on?
-我和贝克特吗  -对
- Me and beckett? - Yeah.
-没有  -听着  如果是我越位了
- No. - Look, man, if I'm offsides--
裁判没有摇旗
No flag on the play.
很好  太好了
Great. Okay. Great.
手持好牌时不要微笑
Don't smile when you have a good card.
你要摆出扑克脸
You need to develop a poker face.
相信我  这招屡试不爽
Trust me. It comes in handy.
也有失效的时候
Except when it doesn't.
什么意思
Wh-what do you mean?
没事
Never mind.
一对皇后
Pair of ladies.
你拿着什么牌
What have you got?
两张国王  我赢了
Two cowboys! I win.
现在谁更胜一筹呢
Who's the daddy now?
你赢的样子像极了奶奶
You win like your grandmother.
结果是我要为你洗一晚的碗
So it looks like I owe you one night of solo dish duty.
而你要为我整理四天床铺
And you owe me four days of bed-making duty,
还要为我的三次水疗和两幅太阳镜埋单
three spa treatments, two pairs of sunglasses
以及欠奶奶一个宝格丽皮包[意大利名牌]
and a Bulgari purse for gram.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我不习惯输
I'm not used to losing.
你好  卡萝
Hey, Carol.
有时间谈谈吗
Got a few minutes?
-哈维叔叔  -你好啊 小家伙
- Uncle Javi! - Hey, what's up, buddy?
-你好  -怎么样了
- What's up? - How you doing?
-很好  -那就好  你又高了
- Good. - Good. Oh, man, you lookin' tall.
这是我的拍档凯文
Mm-hmm. Hey, this is my boy--Kevin.
-你好  我叫蒂姆  -幸会  蒂姆
- Hi. I'm Tim. - Nice to meet you, Tim.
他超爱棒球卡
Hey, he loves baseball cards.
带他上楼去看看你的卡怎样
Why don't you, uh, take him upstairs, show him yours?
-跟我来  -好
- Come on. - Let's go.
你知道多长时间了
How long have you known?
卡萝  告诉我他在哪
Carol, it'll be a lot easier for him
对他有好处
if you just tell me where he is.
好让你去抓他吗
So you can arrest him?
卡萝  他杀了人
Carol, he killed a man.
不可能
No.
尸体上有他的指纹
His prints were on the body.
拜托  不要去找他
Please... Please... Do not try to find him...
现在不行  我们已经很接近了
Not now, not when we are so close.
接近什么
So close to what?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不能说
I can't.
如果你按鼠标按累了  可以换我来
You know, if your mouse finger gets tired, we can switch.
-没事  我不累  -了解
- That's okay. I think I can handle it. - Oh, I get it.
你喜欢掌握主动权
You don't want to give up the driver's seat.
我买了咖啡
Hey, I brought coffee.
不用了
Uh, you know what? It's okay.
戴明已经买了
Demming already brought some.
是吗
Did he now?
我
I...
看  保罗·芬奇
Hey, Paul Finch.
没错  他在观察环境
Oh, yeah. He's casing the place.
-看看他的拍档是谁  -他妻子莫妮卡
- And look who his partner is. - That's his wife Monica.
她明明说自己毫不知情
She said she had no idea what he was doing.
还有人跟他们一伙的
There's someone else with 'em.
那是
That's...
艾克·松顿
Ike Thornton.
如果他为雷辛干活
If he's working for racine,
那他与芬奇一起干什么
what's he doing with finch?
艾克和芬奇是一伙的
So ike was working with finch?
看来是的  我想他是发现
Yeah, it looks that way. I'm guessing he discovered
雷辛将一些有价值的东西放在保险箱
racine was keeping something valuable in the box.
他需要芬奇的帮助来得到它
He needed finch's skills to help him get it.
如果他们一起干活  那他为何杀了他
But if they were working together,why would he kill him?
也许雷辛是对的
Maybe racine was right.
真的是盗亦"无"道
Maybe there is no honor amongst thieves.
也许不是他做的
And maybe he didn't do it.
我们有他在现场的证据
We have him at the scene.
他和芬奇是一伙的  他妻子没和盘托出
Him working with finch, what his wife said, it doesn't add.
肯定另有内幕
Something else is going on.
看来我们很快会知道
Looks like we're about to find out what.
是这样  莫妮卡  我们没兴趣
Here's the thing, Monica, we're not interested
了解你是否帮你丈夫到银行踩点
in whether you helped your husband case the bank.
我们只想找出杀人凶手
All we care about is finding the guy who killed him--
艾克·松顿
Ike thornton.
你们认为是艾克·松顿杀了保罗
You think Ike Thornton killed Paul?
让我告诉你艾克是怎样的人
Let me tell you the kind of man Ike is.
十二年前  他逮捕了抢劫的保罗
About 12 years back, he collared Paul
和他弟弟巴利
and his kid brother Barry on a heist.
艾克看在巴利是初犯  放过了他
Ike saw that Barry was a first-timer, so he cut him a break.
保罗坐了五年牢
Paul went to jail for five years,
却从没忘记艾克的恩情
but he never forgot what Ike did for his brother.
所以他才为艾克出山  为了谢恩
That's why he did this last job with him, as payback.
谢恩害了他  我们在你丈夫身上
Well, payback's a bitch, because we found
找到艾克的指纹
Ike's fingerprints on your husband's body.
我不信
I don't believe it.
你不信没关系
It doesn't matter if you don't believe it.
但事实是艾克当时在场
The fact is, Ike was there.
他折磨并杀死了你丈夫
He tortured and killed your husband.
保险箱里有什么
What was in the box, Monica?
他们从雷辛那里偷走了什么
What did they steal from Racine?
一定是价值连城的东西  所以艾克
It must have been pretty valuable if Ike decided
为了避免分赃才把你丈夫杀了
to kill your husband so he wouldn't have to split it.
分赃  根本没什么好分的
Split it? There was nothing to split.
保险箱里到底是什么
What was in the box?
一本册子  一本账簿
A book. A ledger.
一本账簿
A ledger?
上面记录了雷辛的所有资产状况
Something that showed all of racine's pays and owes
包括不合法的部分
on all of his businesses, not just his legitimate ones.
一本记录了雷辛非法经营状况的
An accounting of all of Racine's illegal operations
账簿很有勒索的价值
could be worth a bundle in blackmail.
如果到手了当然很有价值
It could if they'd gotten it,
但当他们进入银行后却发现保险箱是空的
but when they hit the bank, the box was empty.
空的
Empty?
账簿不在里面
The ledger wasn't there.
所以这个人为了偷老板的账簿
So a guy tortures and kills his partner
决定抢银行
after breaking into a bank
结果扑个空  之后他折磨并杀了同伙
to steal something from his boss that wasn't actually there.
听你这么说是挺疯狂
Well, it sounds crazy when you say it like that.
听着  他曾是我的拍档
Look, I know he was my partner,
但不管我怎么看
but no matter how I slice it,
人都不像是艾克杀的
it makes no sense that Ike would kill Finch.
-贝克特探长  -霍利维尔督察
- Detective Beckett. - Lieutenant Holliwell.
抱歉打断你们  但我的人一直在
Sorry to interrupt, but my team's been up on a wire
监听雷辛组织里
monitoring the cell phones of
几个关键人物的手机
several key members of Racine's organization.
我们在留意是否有人提及艾克·松顿
We've been listening for any mention of Ike Thornton.
然后呢
And?
看来并不只有我们在找艾克·松顿
And it turns out, we're not the only ones looking for him.
雷辛刚出高价买下松顿的人头
Racine just put a price on Thornton's head.
雷辛一定是发现他在追查账簿的事
Racine must have found out he was going after the ledger.
我想你不是唯一一个被你拍档背叛的人
I guess you're not the only one your old partner betrayed.
-卡萝有危险  -你去哪里
- Carol. - Where you going?
如果雷辛要追杀艾克  他会先去
If racine's going after Ike, the first place he's gonna go
艾克的家  他的妻儿有危险
is the same place we went, his wife and kid.
-莱恩  跟上  -好
- Ryan. - Yeah.
我马上通知监视小分队
I'm gonna call the surveillance team.
卡萝
Carol!
卡萝  是我哈维
Carol, it's Javi!
卡萝
Carol!
蒂姆
Timmy!
上楼看看  去
Upstairs. Go.
卡萝
Carol!
蒂姆
Timmy!
没人
Nothing.
他们走了
They're gone.
监视人员说他们没离开过
Surveillance team said they never left.
-他们是怎么  -雷辛做的
- How the hell did they-- - Racine.
让警员盘问下周围的邻居
Have the uniforms canvass the neighbors.
-可能会有目击者  -这就去
- Maybe somebody saw something. - Yeah, on it.
哈维  谢谢你为我儿子做的一切
I appreciate what you done for my boy, Javi.
卡萝和蒂姆呢  他们在哪里
Carol and Tim... where are they?
他们在雷辛找不到的地方
Somewhere where Racine can't find 'em.
我们有同事每周全天候守在这里
We've had guys on this place 24/7.
你是怎么进来的
How the hell did you get in here?
做了三年的隐形人  我来去如风
Three years as a ghost, you learn a few things.
所以内务处是对的
So I.A. was right...
三年前是对的
Three years ago...
现在也是
Now.
你为雷辛卖命
You were working for Racine.
你也这么认为吗
Is that what you believe?
你让我以为你死了
You let me think you were dead.
而现在你把枪口对着我
And now you're holding a burner on me.
哈维  你是一个好警察
You're a good cop, Javi.
如果我放下枪  你会抓我
But I put this down, you gon' take me in.
我不能让你这样做  还不到时候
And I can't let you do that, not yet,
-我们已经很接近了  -接近什么
- not when I'm so close. - So close to what?
警队里有人接受了雷辛的贿赂
There is a dirty cop on Racine's payroll.
为了掩护自己人  雷辛陷害了我
So in order to throw them off his guy, Racine dirtied me up.
而内务处完全相信这个说法
And I.A. bought it hook, line and sinker.
你为什么不对我说
Why didn't you just come to me?
兄弟  你知情的话你也会遭毒手
Look, cases like mine are contagious, brother.
我不能让你重蹈我的覆辙
I couldn't let you catch what I had.
雷辛的内应给了内务处虚假证据
Racine's guy fed them so much garbage,
好让他们把我抓起来
they could lock me up.
如果我真被抓起来了
And if I had let 'em,
在我为自己洗清罪名之前
Racine woulda had me shanked at Rikers
雷辛早就派人在赖克斯岛把我干掉了[纽约市监狱所在地]
before I could clear my name.
-这段时间你去哪了  -在一旁观察学习
- Where you been? - Watching, learning.
所以我才能找到账簿
That's how I found out about the ledger.
-雷辛的资产状况  -上面记录着
- Racine's pays and owes. - Everyone on his payroll,
所有交易  包括陷害我的那名坏警察的
including the dirty cop that set me up.
但账簿并不如你设想般放在银行
But the ledger wasn't in the bank like you thought.
雷辛通过一些途径找到芬奇
Somehow, Racine found finch.
你也在场  我们找到了你的指纹
You were there, man. We found your prints.
哈维  我找到他时他已经死了
He was dead when I found him, Javi.
我只是帮他合上眼  兄弟相信我
I just closed his eyes. Come on, man.
那账簿呢
And the ledger?
我知道账簿在哪里
I know where the ledger is.
哈维  但我需要多点时间
But I need a little more time, Javi.
只要等到明晚
Just until tomorrow night.
你以前一直把徽章带在身边
You used to carry yours with you all the time.
我现在也是
I still do, man.
这表示杀人的另有其人
Then that means there's somebody else mixed up in this,
54分局的人
somebody from the 54th.
不管是谁  是他告诉雷辛我还活着
Whoever it is, they tipped Racine that I'm still alive,
也就是说他们就在身边
which means they're close.
可能是调查此案的一份子
Maybe a part of your investigation.
54分局
54th.
戴明
Demming.
是他
It's him.
肯定是他
Gotta be.
还记得他说是自己要的这个案子吗
Remember how he said he requested this case?
说他酷爱离奇案件
Said he liked the weird ones,
其实是为了替雷辛
but it was just so he could hunt down
找出窃贼
the thieves for Racine.
我早发现他不招人喜欢了
I knew there was something I didn't like about him.
长的太帅了
Too pretty.
他肯定上瑜伽课就为了
Bet he takes yoga classes
-勾引女孩子  -这些年来
- just so he can pick up girls.  - All these years,
他拿着雷辛的钱
he's been lining his pockets with Racine's cash,
却让松顿替他背黑锅
leaving Thornton holding the bag.
可能还定了《纽约客》
Probably subscribes to "The New Yorker",
却从来不看
but doesn't even read it...
这家伙一直在耍我们
the guy's been playing us all along,
利用我们找到芬奇的同伙
using us to find Finch's accomplice.
只不过是把《纽约客》摆在外面充门面
Just leaves copies laying out where people can see 'em.
-我们来让他现出原形  -怎样做呢
- Let's nail the bastard.  - How?
若是他在给雷辛报密
If he was tipping off Racine,
他不会用警区电话
he wouldn't use the precinct phone.
而是手机
He'd use his cell.
我们可以取出手机卡
We could pull his SIM card.
若上面有和雷辛的通话记录
If there are any calls to Racine,
就证据确凿了
we have all the proof we need.
怎样把他的手机弄到手呢
How are we gonna get his phone away from him?
怎么了
What's up, man?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
好久没练了
It's been a while for me.
-好  我会温柔点的  -那太好了
- You know, I'll try to be gentle.  - Oh, you do that.
太猛了吗
Too much for you?
不  我热身比较慢
No, no. I'm just a little slow to get started.
现在找到节奏了
But I think I'm starting to find my rhythm now.
快点  快
Let's go. Hurry up.
怎么了
What?
你好  干什么呢  洗澡吗
Hey, man. What's up? Showering?
-到手了  -走
- Got it.  - Let's go.
有没有松顿的消息
Any news on Thornton?
-没有  -埃斯波西托情况如何
- None.  - How's Esposito taking all this?
你觉得呢
How do you think? I mean, here's a guy
他为了纪念搭档一直
who's been carrying his 54th key for
-戴着54分局的钥匙扣  -我也有那个
- in honor of his partner's sacrifice.  - I had one of those.
-是吗  -是的
- Oh, yeah?  - Yeah.
但几年前弄丢了
But I lost mine years ago.
来
Come on.
这家伙肯定发过很多性短讯
Bet this guy does a lot of sexting, too.
在加载了
It's uploading now.
跟你说
Oh. I gotta tell ya,
我不知道还能坚持多久
I don't know how much longer I can keep this up.
听说想一下棒球会有帮助
You know, I hear it helps if you think about baseball.
不办案的时候
So what do you do for fun, Kate, huh,
你都怎么消遣呢  凯特
when you're not trying to take someone's head off?
事实上我是个宅女
I'm actually kind of a homebody.
遇到你的前一晚
You know, the night before I met you,
我回家看书去了
I went home to read a book.
开玩笑吧
No kidding?
你呢
What about you?
什么  如何消遣
What about me what? What do I do for fun?
还是遇到你的前一晚在做什么
Or what was I doing the night before we met?
说正经的
Seriously...
你为何不直接问我
Why don't you just ask me
是否有芬奇谋杀案的不在场证据
if I have an alibi for Finch's murder?
好吧  那你在哪里
Okay. So where were you?
我通过反向目录查看了所有号码
I ran all his numbers through the reverse directory.
没有异常通话
They're all coming clean.
因为那个人不是戴明
That's because it wasn't Demming.
你的不在场证明证实了
Your alibi checked out.
-谢谢  -他确实在给
- Thank you.  - He really was coaching
一支贫困少年棒球队当教练
an underprivileged youth basketball league.
值得欣慰的是  孩子们那晚赢了比赛
Well, for what it's worth, my kids won that night.
真假
Oh, Jeez.
抱歉  必须排除嫌疑
Sorry, man. Had to rule you out.
继续查案吧  有个奸细在警局
Let's just move on. Look, there's a wrong cop out there.
我们必须找出来
We need to figure out who it is.
你知道过去10年中
Do you know how many cops
有多少警察在54分局工作过吗
have been through the 54th in the last 10 years?
成百个  甚至上千个
Hundreds, maybe thousands.
不管是谁  那个人都不简单
Well, whoever it was was very good.
他不可能替恶人卖命
You don't work the other side
却不引起内务处的注意
without arousing I.A. suspicion
除非你相当谨慎
unless you know what you're doing.
我们不可能找到他了  就算找到
Yeah, we're never gonna find him, not
-也来不及了  -来不及什么
- in time anyway.  - In time for what?
我要去走走
I gotta take a walk.
你不是说要走走吗
Hey, I thought you were going for a walk.
你想做什么
What do you want?
松顿今晚要去偷账簿  是不是
Thornton's going after the ledger tonight, isn't he?
他独自追查了三年了
The man's been on the run for three years,
和家人不得不分开
separated from his family.
我必须帮他  别阻止我
I gotta help the guy, so don't try to stop me.
我不是要阻止你
I'm not.
-我要和你一起去  -不  你不能去
- I'm going with you.  - No, you're not.
我是你搭档
I'm your partner.
不管怎样我都和你一起行动
That means I'm with you till the wheels fall off.
我知道  兄弟
I know, bro.
但  万一发生意外
But... I'm gonna need you to get my back
得需要你帮忙照应  明白吗
if things go wrong, all right?
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
案情有进展了吧  同志们
Tell me you got something, people.
很抱歉  长官  我们陷入了死局
Unfortunately, Sir, we are dead in the water.
不  没有
No... we're not.
若松顿没有替雷辛做事
If Thornton never worked for Racine,
那三年前有人向内务处报了假情报
then someone lied to I.A. three years ago.
来洗清真正奸细的嫌疑
To throw suspicion from the real dirty cop.
所以和内务处谈话的那个人
So whoever I.A. was talking to,
肯定知道谁是奸细
they must know who the real dirty cop is.
我们只需要从霍利威尔那里搞一份
All we need to do is get the name of the informant
举报人名单然后审问他
from Holliwell and run him down.
说起来容易
Easier said than done.
内务处官员是不可能泄露
There's no way an I.A. officer is gonna give up the name
-重要举报人姓名的  -不一定
- of a confidential informant.  -We'll see about that.
你真的想好了吗
You sure you're ready to bet your badge on this?
-风险很大的  -你是我搭档
- Pretty long odds.  - You're my partner.
你确定能进得了雷辛的办公室吗
You sure you can get us in Racine's office?
相信我
Trust me.
我已经查探三年了
I've been casing the joint for three years.
行动吧
Let's roll.
长官  你怎么弄到的
Sir, how did you do it?
投其所好  各取所需
Pulling strings and trading favors.
怎么回事
This can't be right.
在三年前对艾克·松顿的调查报告上
The investigation against Ike Thornton three years ago,
霍利威尔督察把哈维尔·埃斯波西托警探
Lieutenant Holliwell lists his chief informant
列为重要举报人
as Detective Javier Esposito.
-混蛋  -什么意思
- Son of a bitch.  - What does that mean?
根本没有举报人
It means there was no informant.
长官  有没有办法查到
Sir, is there any way to find out
霍利威尔是否在54分局工作过
if Holliwell served at the  54th?
快点  兄弟  怎么要这么久
Come on, bro. What the hell's taking so long?
我都可以咬穿保险箱了
I could have chewed through that by now.
找到了
There we go.
内务处的好处就是
Nice thing about Internal Affairs...
我们的工作就是监视其他警察
It's our job to monitor other cops.
你该把手机关死的
You should've turned your cell phone off completely,
埃斯波西托
Esposito,
-全球定位你是知道的  -一直是你
- You know, with GPS and all.  - All this time, it was you.
我猜你总要找来的
I figured you'd come for that sooner or later.
失策啊
Big mistake.
把账簿扔过来
Toss the ledger over here.
快扔
Throw it!
松顿  若我是你的话
See, if I were you Thornton...
我会继续装死
I woulda just stayed dead.
你不配和我比  我是警察
Well, you're not me. I'm a cop.
我可不认为你是警察  你是个通缉犯
Oh, I beg to differ, buddy. You're a wanted criminal.
问埃斯波西托好了
Just ask Esposito over here.
为了逮捕你 他光荣牺牲
He died trying to apprehend you.
我唯一的遗憾就是
My only regret is that I...
出现的太晚了  没能救他
I showed up too late to save him.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
在了结之前
Look, there's something I want to say
我想说几句
before we're done here.
谢谢你支持我
Thanks for backing me up.
我们一直合作的很愉快
Lot of good that did us.
松顿  杀了你我将获得
I am going to get the medal of valor
-英勇勋章  -不  我说真的
- for killing you, Thornton.  - No, I'm serious, man.
谢谢你在"背后"支持我
Thanks for having my back.
你们来了真是太好了  他们想杀我
Thank god you're here. They tried to kill me.
埃斯波西托和松顿  他们都参与了
Esposito and Thornton, they're both in on it.
放下枪  不然我开枪了
Drop it or I will drop you.
霍利威尔  你知道规矩  把手举好
You know the drill, Holliwell. Keep 'em up.
霍利威尔督察
Lieutenant Holliwell,
你因谋杀保罗·芬奇被捕
You're under arrest for the murder of Paul Finch.
埃斯波西托呢
Where's Esposito?
埃斯波西托在哪里
Where's esposito?!
埃斯波西托
Esposito?!
这里  有个警员受伤了
Yeah. We got an officer down.
威廉16号  休斯顿街3471号
William 16, William 16, need an ambulance
呼叫救护车
at 3471 Houston.
我没事  子弹没在身体里
I'm cool. It was a clean exit.
霍利威尔呢
Holliwell?
-抓到他了  账簿也拿到了  -很好
- Yeah, we got him and the ledger.  - Good.
-艾克  -嗯
- Ike.  - Yeah.
-这是我搭档  莱恩  -你好
- This my partner--Ryan.  - Hey.
这是我另一个搭档
And this is my other partner...
卡塞尔
Castle.
你好
Hey, man.
有了霍利威尔的证词和账簿
And with Holliwell's testimony and the ledger,
我们有足够的证据逮捕雷辛
we now have enough evidence to arrest Racine.
行  但我不明白的是
Okay, but what I don't understand
你怎么会和松顿一起
is how the hell you ended up
出现在雷辛的办公室
in Racine's office with Thornton.
长官  我
Sir, I--
抱歉  长官  我以为都汇报清楚了
Oh, I-I'm sorry, sir. I thought we made that clear.
当我们接到报案
Esposito was with us
说雷辛办公室有劫案发生的时候
when we responded to a robbery in progress call
埃斯波西托和我们在一起
at Racine's office.
那谁报的警呢
And who made the call?
是一个公民
Uh, the call was made by a private citizen
他不想公开名字
who wishes to remain anonymous.
那我需要那个公民来
Well, I may need a private citizen
帮我收拾这烂摊子
to help me write up this damn mess.
我很乐意提供我的专长
I'd be happy to lend my expertise.
那
So...
你们不是来放我的吧
I know you're not turning me loose.
-只是离监休假  -有好戏给你看
- Just a furlough.  - We got something we want you to see.
你成功了  兄弟
You did it, bro.
好消息是
And the best news is...
你是自由身了
you're free to go.
就我所知芬奇是单独行动的
As far as I'm concerned, Finch acted alone.
这是我的案子  我结案了
It's my case. I'm closing it.
雷辛近期也不会上诉了
And I don't see Racine pressing charges anytime soon.
现在  他想否认账簿是他的
Right now, he's trying to deny that the ledger is his.
艾克  你该回家了
It's time for you to go home, Ike.
这里总有这么多乐趣吗
So is it always this much fun up here?
我们有风光的时候
We have our moments.
现在你知道我不是奸细了
So now that you know I'm not a dirty cop,
不论何时  只要你想找陪练
anytime you need a sparring partner...
谢谢
Thanks.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry. What?